A Register of the Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka records
Hoover Institution Archives
Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka records
1917-1984.
2008C48
Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka.
2 microfilm reels (0.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, financial records, and photographs, relating to operations of the Kornilovskii Polk during the Russian Civil War, and to postwar activities of its veterans in emigration.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
The collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Originals
In part, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers consist of select records of the Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka, the Union of Kornilov Shock Regiment Veterans, one of the units of the White Army during the Russian Civil War. The records relate to the fate of the regiment's members in the emigration, dating from 1921 to 1980, and relating to their presence in Bulgaria, Serbia, France, Belgium and other European countries. Included among the documents are correspondence, financial records, membership lists, orders, photographs, and reports.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Russia (Territory under White armies, 1918-1920) Dobrovol'cheskaia armiia.; Kornilovskii polk.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Russia--Emigration and immigration.
Container List
- Office File, 1921-1984. (Box 1)
  Correspondence, financial documents, Gallipoli file, lists, Mikhail Nikolaevich Levitin file, orders, printed matter, reports. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence, 1924-1968 and undated.; See also Mikhail Nikolaevich Levitin file (Folder 1: 1)
  - Financial documents
    - General, 1922-1930 (Folder 1: 2)
    - Property, 1921-1924; 1934 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Receipts, 1922-1923 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Gallipoli file, 1922-1924 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Lists of members
    - Deceased (Folder 1: 6)
    - First Kuban' Campaign (compiled by N. V. Skidan, 1971) (Folder 1: 7)
    - General (Folder 1: 8)
    - Paris section (Folder 1: 9)
    - South America (Folder 1: 10)
  - Mikhail Nikolaevich Levitin file, 1931-1975 and undated
    - Correspondence, 1931-1975
      - Incoming, 1931-1975 (Folder 1: 11)
      - Outgoing, 1931; 1968-69 (Folder 1: 12)
    - Writings, 1963 and undated
      - "Orlovo-Kromskaia operatsiia,", n.d. (Folder 1: 13)
        Typescript
      - "Sluchai ob ukhodie nashego k[omandi]ra K(?)," (Folder 1: 14)
        Holograph
      - "Opisanie boia Kornilovskoi udarnoi divizii 25-go maia 1920-go g.,", 1963. (Folder 1: 15)
  - Orders, 1922-1972 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Printed matter
    - General, 1931-1970 and undated (Folder 1: 17)
    - Clippings, 1933; 1984 and undated (Folder 1: 18)
    - Informatsiia I otdiela ROVS, 1924; 1969, n.d. (Folder 1: 19)
    - Informatsionnyi biulleten'/list, 1931; 1972, n.d. (Folder 1: 20)
    - Kornilovskii udarnyi polk, 1936 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      (signed by General N. V. Skoblin, 1937)
  - Reports
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 2: 2)
    - 1965 (Folder 2: 3)
      (incomplete)
- Photographs, 1917-1980 and undated.
  Members in Bulgaria (1926) and other countries, gravesites, annual meetings. Arranged according to original order
  - Bulgaria, 1926. (Folder 2: 4)
    One album containing one hundred sixteen prints of regiment members, each indentified
  - Gravesites of deceased members and remembrance services, undated. (Folder 2: 5)
    One hundred fifty-six prints
  - Members, 1917-1980. (Folder 2: 6-7)
    Three hundred eighteen prints taken in different countries (Belgium, Bulgaria, Serbia, Spain and others), include identifying information